[
  {
    "_id": 1,
    "question": "How do you declare a two-dimensional array in Java?",
    "options": [
      "int[][] array;",
      "array[] = new int[2][2];",
      "int[] array = new int[2,2];",
      "int[2][2] array;"
    ],
    "answer": 1,
    "tags": ["java", "arrays"],
    "contentType": { "questionType": "text", "answerType": "text" }
  },
  {
    "_id": 2,
    "question": "Which of the keyword is used to define a constant in Java?",
    "options": ["var", "final", "static", "const"],
    "answer": 1,
    "tags": ["java", "variables", "basics"],
    "contentType": { "questionType": "text", "answerType": "text" }
  },
  {
    "_id": 3,
    "question": "What is the purpose of the 'break' statement in a Java switch-case statement?",
    "options": [
      "To exit the loop",
      "To skip the current iteration",
      "To terminate the switch-case block",
      "To continue to the next case"
    ],
    "answer": 2,
    "tags": ["java", "controlFlow"],
    "contentType": { "questionType": "text", "answerType": "text" }
  },
  {
    "_id": 4,
    "question": "Which Java access modifier allows a class to be accessed from any other class?",
    "options": ["private", "protected", "package-private", "public"],
    "answer": 3,
    "tags": ["java", "accessModifiers"],
    "contentType": { "questionType": "text", "answerType": "text" }
  },
  {
    "_id": 5,
    "question": "In Java, what is the purpose of the 'super' keyword?",
    "options": [
      "To access the superclass constructor",
      "To call a static method",
      "To declare a constant",
      "To create a new object"
    ],
    "answer": 0,
    "tags": ["java", "inheritance"],
    "contentType": { "questionType": "text", "answerType": "text" }
  },
  {
    "_id": 6,
    "question": "Which data structure is used to implement a stack in Java?",
    "options": ["ArrayList", "LinkedList", "Array", "Stack"],
    "answer": 0,
    "tags": ["java", "dataStructures"],
    "contentType": { "questionType": "text", "answerType": "text" }
  },
  {
    "_id": 7,
    "question": "What is the main purpose of the 'finally' block in a Java try-catch-finally statement?",
    "options": [
      "To catch exceptions",
      "To handle exceptions",
      "To execute code regardless of exceptions",
      "To rethrow exceptions"
    ],
    "answer": 2,
    "tags": ["java", "exceptionHandling"],
    "contentType": { "questionType": "text", "answerType": "text" }
  },
  {
    "_id": 8,
    "question": "Which Java interface is used to implement event handling for graphical user interfaces?",
    "options": ["Runnable", "Serializable", "MouseListener", "Comparable"],
    "answer": 2,
    "tags": ["java", "GUI"],
    "contentType": { "questionType": "text", "answerType": "text" }
  },
  {
    "_id": 9,
    "question": "What is the default value of a Java instance variable of type int?",
    "options": ["0", "1", "null", "undefined"],
    "answer": 0,
    "tags": ["java", "variables"],
    "contentType": { "questionType": "text", "answerType": "text" }
  },
  {
    "_id": 10,
    "question": "What is the output of the following Java code snippet?\n\n```\npublic class Main {\n  public static void main(String[] args) {\n    int x = 5;\n    System.out.println(x++ + ++x);\n  }\n}\n```",
    "options": ["10", "11", "12", "13"],
    "answer": 3,
    "tags": ["java", "operators"],
    "contentType": { "questionType": "code", "answerType": "text" }
  },
  {
    "_id": 11,
    "question": "Which of the following is a front-end JavaScript framework?",
    "options": ["Angular", "Spring Boot", "Django", "Express"],
    "answer": 0,
    "tags": ["webDevelopment", "javascript"],
    "contentType": { "questionType": "text", "answerType": "text" }
  },
  {
    "_id": 12,
    "question": "What does npm stans for",
    "options": [
      "node program manager",
      "new project manager",
      "node package manager",
      "nodejs project manager"
    ],
    "answer": 2,
    "tags": ["basics", "javascript"],
    "contentType": { "questionType": "text", "answerType": "text" }
  },
  {
    "_id": 13,
    "question": "Which is not a valid Javascript keyword",
    "options": ["let", "then", "implements", "import"],
    "answer": 2,
    "tags": ["basics", "javascript"],
    "contentType": { "questionType": "text", "answerType": "text" }
  },
  {
    "_id": 14,
    "question": "JavaScript is Multithreaded , Ture or False?",
    "options": ["True", "False"],
    "answer": 0,
    "tags": ["basics", "javascript"],
    "contentType": { "questionType": "text", "answerType": "text" }
  }
]
